

Gazi Tawsif Torabi

Video Editor & Cinematographer

Mirpur, Dhaka (Contact for Detailed Address) Dhaka - 1216 (+88) 0155 3260 358 tawsiftorabi.jr@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Professional video editor with 4+ years of experience with video editing and color grading skills and knowledge of the latest video editing software from Adobe and editing techniques. Started as a self-learner independent video editor. Then joined a startup production company as a cinematographer and video editor.

EXPERIENCE

Cloud's Den, Mirpur-14 — Cinematographer & Editor

February 2018 - August 2019

Worked as Cinematographer, Editor & Screenplay Writer.

- Edited and animated 1 Television Commercial.
- Edited 15+ wedding cinematic videos.
- Worked as a wedding cinematographer.
- Designed and animated the company Logo.
- Post-Production Audio works.

Inovasi Films, Niketan — *Video Editor*

February 2021 - April 2021

Worked as Video Editor, Sound Editor & Subtitle Writer.

- Edited 6 Television Documentaries for the Ministry of Agriculture, this project is yet to be aired.
- Wrote subtitles for 4 videos to be presented to representatives of The World Bank.
- Recorded and Edited voiceovers for television-grade production.
- Post-Production Audio works.
- Some minor Graphics and Illustration works for some videos.

WORK SKILLS

- 1. Video Editing
- 2. Cinematography & Story Telling
- 3. Color Grading
- 4. Audio Mixing & Mastering
- 5. Voice Over
- 6. Creating 2D Artwork
- 7. Vector Illustration

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Adobe Photoshop CC
- Adobe Illustrator CC
- FL Studio
- Audacity
- OBS Studio
- Adobe After Effects
- Adobe Audition
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Google Spreadsheets

LANGUAGES

Bangla & English

Travelia, Maniknagar — Creative Content & Partner Relation Officer

August 2019 - December 2020

Worked as Graphic Designer, Creative Content Creator, Video Editor & Motion Graphic Designer.

- Edited and animated 20+ animated tutorial videos.
- Worked on voiceovers.
- Designed and animated the company Logo.
- Managed creative content as managing officer.

Freelance Artist, Cinematographer & Photographer

In July 2017

I started working as a freelance cinematographer & photographer. Worked in enormous music videos, and social media commercials. Here's the portfolio Facebook page and Behance page

- Tawsif Torabi on Behance
- Torabi's Studio | Facebook

Genji Shomaddar, Mirpur-14 — *Graphic Designer*

April 2019 - April 2020

Worked as a graphic designer. Designed hand-drawn and designed T-Shirt for this online e-commerce shop.

ACTIVITIES

UIU Theatre & Film Club, Badda — Asst. Head of Short Films

October 2020 - Present

Joined as a General Member and promoted to Asst. Head of Films department. Worked on three film production on behalf of UIU Theatre & Film Club.

Pix-L, Paltan — Vice President – Technical

May 2019 - May 2020

Joined as a General Member in 2018 and promoted to Executive core to vice president in 2019.

SPSC Photography Club, Mirpur-14 — *Mentor & Core Member*

March 2018 - May 2019

Founding executive member and "Cinematography and Editing" mentor of Shaheed Police Smrity College Photography Club.

EDUCATION

Shaheed Police Smrity College, Mirpur-14 — SSC, HSC

January 2007 - May 2019 High School Graduated.

United International University, Badda — *BsCSE*

January 2020 - Present

Undergraduate Student.



PROJECTS LIST

- 1. <u>UIU Theatre and Film Club OVC</u> 2021
- 2. Oshoriri Music Video 2021
- 3. <u>UIU Robotics event "Innobotics 2020" Television Commercial</u> 2020
- 4. <u>Elora's Closet OVC #1</u> 2020
- 5. <u>Elora's Closet OVC #2</u> 2020
- 6. <u>System Of A Down Aerials (Bass Cover by Bass Conjunction)</u> 2019

- 7. Royal Blood Out Of the Black Cover Music Video 2019
- 8. <u>Cloud's Den Photography Exhibition Promo</u> 2019
- 9. Rupok Introduction OVC 2018
- 10. SPSC SSC Batch Tour Documentary Video 2018
- 11. SPSC HSC Batch Tour Documentary Video 2018

CONTENT LIBRARY

- 1. Video and Audio Production Collaboration Bass Conjunction
- 2. Youtube Channel <u>Tawsif Torabi</u>
- 3. Soundcloud Profile <u>Tawsif Torabi</u>
- 4. My Content Creator Channel Amazing Vangari